allegiantair.com 2019-05-01

# Allegiant Air

Effective January 21, 2019

Allegiant Air is concerned about your right to privacy. When you visit the Allegiant Air website, you can be assured that any information you share with us will be treated confidentially.

The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) requires you to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender for the purpose of watch list screening, under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49 C.F.R parts 1540 and 1560. You may also provide your Redress Number or Known Traveler Number, if available. Failure to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender may result in denial of transport or denial of authority to enter the boarding area. TSA may share information you provide with law enforcement or intelligence agencies or others under its published system of records notice. For more on TSA privacy policies, or to review the system of records notice and the privacy policy impact assessment, please see the TSA website at [www.tsa.gov](https://www.tsa.gov/).

**Data we collect**

Personal information from you and the people who travel with you (name, gender, date of birth, phone number, email address, disability information, special assistance requests such as dietary/wheelchair/oxygen/other medical needs, service animals needs, known travel and redress numbers, credit card information, billing address, emergency contact, geolocation).

Products and services you purchase from us (including but not limited to flights, travel dates, hotels, rental cars, seats, bags, confirmation codes, entertainment, events). Transactional and online activity data in your use of our websites or apps. All such data is aggregated and anonymized for analytical use.

Your communications to us (emails, phone calls, social media, survey responses, letters).

**How we collect your data**

Your data is collected on-line, over the phone, at an airport kiosk, by using a self-service device or inflight.

**How we use your data**

We use your data to: provide you with the purchased services; provide you with operational information such as updates on flight times and dates; remind you about incomplete bookings; provide you with assistance in your travel; comply with TSA regulatory requirements; improve our products and services; send you marketing communications; comply with our record keeping requirements.

**How long we keep your data**

Your data is retained in our systems for as long as you continue being our customer and as long as is mandated by local, state and federal laws and regulations.

**E-mail addresses**

E-mail addresses provided by you to Allegiant Air shall not be shared with any third parties that are not contractually obligated to a relationship with Allegiant Air or Allegiant Travel. Your email address may be shared with our affiliates and subsidiaries within Allegiant Travel Company, such as Sunseeker, Teesnap, G4CE, etc.

**Use of Cookies & How We Use Your Information**

A cookie is a small data file that websites often store on your computer's hard drive when you visit. Allegiant Air uses cookies, but we do not store personally identifiable information in your cookie.

We use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our website in a manner that does not identify you. This information helps us to serve you better by improving our site design, as well as our products, services, contests, and promotions.

We allow certain third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, e-mail address, telephone number or any other personally identifiable information) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Such third parties do not collect personally identifiable information.

In order to provide you with certain services, we may share relevant customer information (for example: name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, etc.) with our affiliates, as well as with unaffiliated third parties who perform services for Allegiant Air (e.g., rental car, lodging and travel accommodation companies, information systems maintenance and development providers, data archiving, customer communication, marketing and similar services). Please refer to the websites of such third parties and suppliers for their privacy policies and other information. Otherwise, the only instances that would require us to disclose customer information is to verify billing information with the customer's financial institution, to monitor for credit card fraud detection, under legal subpoena or other valid law enforcement requests

**Security**

We use Transport Layer Security (TLS) 256 bit encryption to protect your personal information. This keeps the data that you send to Allegiant Air private and secure. This technology ensures the safety of transmitting personal information over the internet.

In addition, we use Extended Validation Certificate, which adds an additional layer of security to the website.

**Policy Changes**

Allegiant Air reserves the right to modify its Privacy Policy at any time. In the event that we make a material change to our policy we will post a notice of the change on this page.

**More Questions?**

Please visit our Contact Us page.
